talktalkmembers.com 2011-12-27

# TalkTalk Members - Privacy Policy

##  Privacy Policy 

Thursday, 27 September 2007 

## How your personal information is used by TalkTalk Telecom Limited

When you use the Web site at [http://www.talktalkmembers.com/]() we may ask you to provide certain information.

We may share your information with companies within the TalkTalk Group Limited group of companies and other carefully selected third parties for the purposes described in this policy and, in the event that we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, you agree that your information may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party. These purposes may include:

  * details you give us on application forms,
  * details you give us so that we can provide you with goods and services,
  * details you give us through use of our Web site.

You agree that we may use and update this centrally held information:

  * to provide you with other services;
  * to recover debts;
  * to prevent and detect fraud;
  * to update our records about you;
  * to prevent money laundering; and
  * to check your identity.

We may also use your information for research and statistical analysis with the aim of improving our services. If you request it, on payment of a fee, which is currently £10, we will provide you with a copy of the personal information to which you are entitled that we hold about you.

The information we hold about you is confidential. We will only disclose it outside the TalkTalk Group Limited group of companies when:

  * you give us your consent,
  * it is needed by certain reputable third parties involved in running accounts and/or providing services for you (for example, credit reference agencies who do credit checks for us),
  * in order to obtain professional advice,
  * we or others need to investigate or prevent crime (e.g. to fraud prevention agencies),
  * the law permits or requires it, or any regulatory or governmental body requests or requires it, even without your consent, or,
  * there is a duty to the public to reveal the information.

We may administer your account and provide other services from centres in countries outside Europe that do not always have the same standard of data protection laws as the UK. However, we will have a contract in place to ensure that your information is adequately protected, and we will remain bound by our obligations under the Data Protection Act even when your personal information is processed outside Europe.

## Use of cookies

This Web site uses cookies. Cookies collect information about your use of the Web site, including things like your connection speed, details of your operating system, the time and duration of your visit and your IP address. The information collected by cookies enables us to understand the use of our site, including the number of visitors we have, the pages viewed per session, time exposed to particular pages etc.

This in turn helps us to provide you with a better experience, since we can evaluate the level of interest in the content of our Web site and tailor it accordingly. We do not store information obtained from cookies alongside your personal information and we will not attempt to personally identify you from your IP address unless required to as a matter of law or regulation or in order to protect our or our other customers' rights. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser options so that you will not receive cookies and you can also delete existing cookies from your browser. However, you may find that some parts of the site will not function properly if you refuse cookies.

## Children and TalkTalk

We do not specifically collect information about children and believe that children should always get the consent of their parents before giving out any personal information. Where children are specifically encouraged to participate on the Web site, they will always be advised that they should seek parental permission before they continue with the activity. We recommend that parents actively participate and where possible monitor their children's use of the internet and the Web site.

## Monitoring

We may monitor, record, store and use any telephone, email or other electronic communications with you for training purposes, so that we can check any instructions given to us and to improve the quality of our customer service.

We will monitor network traffic from time to time for the purposes of backup and problem solving and in order to ensure that you are not misusing any of the services provided to you.

## Protecting your privacy

To the extent that sensitive personal data is processed about you, we will employ appropriate security measures given the nature of that data. However, you recognise that your use of the Internet and our Web site is entirely at your own risk. We have tried to create a secure and reliable Web site for our users. However, we have no responsibility or liability for the security of personal information transmitted via the Internet.

We may need to provide some of your personal information to third parties that we use for the purposes of delivering specific services to you.

Our Web site may provide links and/or banner advertisements to third party sites. Please note that we are not responsible for, and have no control over, information that is submitted to or collected by these third parties. Since we do not control those Web sites, you are responsible for reviewing and abiding by the privacy policies of these third party sites.

## Accurate information

We may check what you have told us and share that information with fraud prevention agencies. It is important that you give us accurate information. If you give us false or inaccurate data and we suspect fraud we will record this at the fraud prevention agencies.

You are responsible for informing us that your personal details have changed: for example, a change of address or to your title. You confirm that you will inform us of any change to your personal information as soon as is reasonably practicable in order that we may update our records. Please note that notification of any change to your personal information must be in writing (to the address below), and should include your account and/or telephone numbers with us.

If you feel your privacy has been breached by us, then please write to:

TalkTalk, Data Protection Offcie, PO BOX 390, Southampton, SO30 9AQ 

## Changes to privacy policy

Please note that this policy will be reviewed, and may change, from time to time. The revised policy will be posted to this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it.

## Your consent

By using this Web site you are consenting to this privacy policy. We may in the future change this policy, and if we do so we will post the amended policy on this Web site.

## Decision making

Any decision made by us in relation to the services provided to you shall be final.
